efanniemae.com 2017-09-25

# Online Privacy Notice | Fannie Mae

Fannie Mae respects your concerns about privacy and values its relationship with you. This Online Privacy Notice applies to the following Fannie Mae Web sites (our "Sites") 

  * **FannieMae.com**
  * **FutureHousingLeaders.com**
  * **KnowYourOptions.com**
  * **HomePath.com**
  * **TheHomeStory.com**

This Online Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on our Sites, how we use the information, with whom we share the information, and the choices you can make about our use of the information. We also describe the measures we take to protect the security of the information and how you can contact us about our privacy practices.

This Online Privacy Notice does not apply to information provided to us by business entities or individuals acting in a professional capacity using our technology applications, even if launched through FannieMae.com. If you use any of our technology applications in the course of your business with us, information you submit will be governed by our agreement with you governing the use of that application. We will only use and disclose such information in accordance with that agreement and all applicable laws.  

**Information We Collect**  
We may obtain certain personal information (such as name and other contact details) through our Sites. Here are the most common types of information: 

  * Contact information (such as name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number and fax number);
  * Login and access credentials (such as username and password);
  * Information about your property or mortgage loan;
  * Age and gender;
  * Real estate license number;
  * Responses to brief online surveys; or
  * Comments you submit through our Sites. 

This information is actively provided to us by you on a voluntary basis, not as a result of your using or visiting our Sites.  
We offer visitors to our Sites various services, which we may change from time to time. We may ask you to submit certain personal information so we can provide you with these services.

When you visit our Sites, we and our third party service providers collect information through automated technologies such as cookies, web server logs, and web beacons. We and our third party service providers may combine this information with the personal information that we collect about you. A "cookie" is a file that Web sites send to a visitor's computer or other Internet-connected device to uniquely identify the visitor's browser or to store information or settings in the browser. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Sites, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process or to allow us to track your activities at our Sites.

Disabling Cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our Site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the Site, but some features may not function.

Web Beacons. A "web beacon," also known as an Internet tag, pixel tag or clear GIF, links web pages to web servers and their cookies and may be used to transmit information collected through cookies back to a web server. The information collected using these tools may include your IP address, browser characteristics, operating system, the address of the web page that referred you to our Site, dates and times of Site visits, the language your system uses, and the country and time zone in which your device is located. These technologies permit the collection of "clickstream data," which may include a log of content you access while browsing a website.

Third-Party Analytics. On some of our Sites we use third-party web analytics services, such as Google Analytics and UserZoom. These services may rely upon technologies such as cookies, web server logs and web beacons to help us analyze how visitors reach and interact with our Sites. The information collected through these means (including IP address) is disclosed to or collected directly by these service providers. In Google Analytics, we have enabled “Demographics and Interest Reports,” a Google Analytics Advertising Feature which collects data about web traffic via Google Advertising Cookies that were previously placed on your web browser. This Analytics Advertising Feature allows Google to provide us information concerning visitor demographics, such as age and gender, along with information related to the interests visitors express through their online browsing and purchasing activities. If your Google Account settings permit Google to use the information Google has collected about you to personalize advertisements, Google Analytics will use this information to identify other devices you use for advertising purposes. Please see the Cross Device Use section below. To learn more about Google Advertising Cookies and how to manage cookies within your browser, [click here](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/). To opt out of Google Analytics, [click here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/). To learn more about Google's additional collection and analysis of information by automated means, including how to opt out, [click here](http://www.google.com/analytics/learn/privacy.html). To learn more about UserZoom’s collection and analysis of information by automated means, including how to opt out, [click here](https://s2.userzoom.com/s/ct/ct.aspx?s=C492S21&v=ALL#TOU).

Cross Device Use. We and our third party service providers may use the information that we collect about you (whether directly from you from our Sites, through your device(s), or from a third party) to help us and our third party service providers identify other devices that you use (e.g., a mobile phone, tablet, other computer, etc.). We, and our third party service providers also may use the cross-device tracking and other information we learn about you to serve targeted advertising on your devices and to send you emails. To opt out of cross-device advertising, you may opt out of Google Analytics as described in the Third-Party Analytics section above or follow the instructions set forth in the Third-Party Ad Networks section below. Please note:  if you opt out of these targeted advertising cookies, your opt out will be specific to the web browser or mobile device from which you accessed the opt out. If you use multiple devices or browsers, you will need to opt out each browser or device that you use.

Third-Party Ad Networks. We also use third parties such as network advertisers to promote our Sites on third-party websites or other media (e.g., social networking platforms) and learn about visitors to our Sites. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested and learn more about our visitors online activities. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons, Flash LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one.

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [DAA companies](http://www.aboutads.info/participating/). You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) [Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and their choices regarding having information used by [NAI members](http://www.networkadvertising.org/participating-networks).

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA [Consumer Choice Page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) or the NAI [Consumer Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA or NAI websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) or the NAI’s website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/>.

**Do-Not-Track**  
We do not block nor identify "do not track" signals sent by your browser or other mechanism that provides you a choice regarding the collection of personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across third party Web sites and online services.

**How We Use the Information We Collect**  
We may use the information we collect to: 

  * Verify your identity;
  * Provide, administer and communicate with you about products, services, and events;
  * Create, administer and communicate with you about your online account or subscription;
  * Process, evaluate and respond to your requests, inquiries and applications;
  * Provide and administer communications tools available through our sites, such as tools for submitting online offers to purchase homes owned by Fannie Mae;
  * Operate, evaluate and improve our business (including developing new products and services; managing our communications; performing market research; managing our advertising and marketing; analyzing our products, services and our sites; administering our sites; and performing accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation and collection activities);
  * Protect against and prevent fraud, unauthorized activity, claims and other liabilities; or
  * Comply with and enforce applicable legal requirements, industry standards and our policies and terms of use  

We also may use the information in other ways for which we provide specific notice at the time of collection. 

**Sharing of Information**  
We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information we collect on our Sites, except as described here. We may share the information with our service providers who perform services on our behalf. These service providers are not authorized by us to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or comply with legal requirements. We may also provide personal information to third parties such as technology providers to enable such third parties to perform business, professional and technical support functions for us, our Sites or for you. On certain Sites, we provide tools to allow real estate agents to communicate with each other to negotiate transactions. In the course of these communications, they may use our tools to share personal information about the parties they represent. 

In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process (such as a court order), (ii) in response to a request by law enforcement authorities or regulatory agencies, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We also reserve the right to transfer personal information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use personal information you have provided to us on our Sites in a manner that is consistent with this Online Privacy Notice. 

**Your Rights and Choices**  
We offer you certain choices about how we communicate with you and what information we collect from you. Some of our Sites provide features that allow you to (i) access and update personal information you have provided there or (ii) register your communications preferences, such as by telling us not to send you marketing materials. You also may contact us as described in the How To Contact Us section below to update your preferences, ask us to remove your information from our mailing lists or submit other requests. Business contacts may be required to receive certain information in the course of doing business with Fannie Mae.  

**How We Protect Personal Information**  
We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the personal information we collect on our Sites against accidental, unlawful or unauthorized destruction, loss, alteration, access, disclosure or use. 

**Links to Other Web Sites, Features, and Embedded Content**  
For your convenience and information, our Sites may provide links to other Web sites or online services, including social media sites, or present content or features from other Web sites or other third parties. These Web sites may operate independently from Fannie Mae. The Web sites may have their own privacy notices or policies, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked Web site or pages containing content hosted by other Web sites. To the extent such Web sites are not owned or controlled by Fannie Mae, we are not responsible for the Web site's content, any use of the Web site, or the privacy practices of the Web site. 

**Updates to Our Online Privacy Notice**  
This Online Privacy Notice may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our personal information practices. We will post a prominent notice on our Sites to notify you of any significant changes to this Online Privacy Notice, indicate when it was most recently updated and its effective date. Unless otherwise stated, changes in our personal information practices are immediately applicable to you upon publication of the revised Online Privacy Notice. Information collected from Fannie Mae-controlled Web sites not listed above but posting this Online Privacy Notice, is, by default, subject to this Online Privacy Notice. 

How to Contact Us  
If you have any questions or comments about this Online Privacy Notice, please:

Write to:  
Fannie Mae  
3900 Wisconsin Ave., NW  
Washington, DC 20016 

E-mail:  
Effective date: August 15, 2017

\- See more at: http://fanniemae.com/portal/privacy-statement.html#sthash.nf620hI6.dpuf
